感觉就跟梦一样
Felt like a dream.
发生什么了
What happened?
你哭了  然后...
You cried and...
我抱着你  你就睡过去了
I held you, and you fell asleep.
然后我们就这样了
And here we are.
我们就这样了
Here we are.
我不想出去
I don't want to go out there.
你不用出去  现在不用
You don't have to -- not yet.
但是终究得出去
But eventually.
终究得出去
Eventually.
我以前常梦到早晨的阳光
I used to dream about the morning sunlight.
梦中阳光渗过指尖
I'd run my hand through it in my dream.
就是这样
Like this.
现在是真的了
And now it's real.
是啊
It is.
我该满心欢喜才是
I should be filled with joy.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
我也是
Me too.
你知道去哪里吗
Do you know where you're going?
不知道
No.
你呢
Do you?
不知道
No.
昭雪
第二季第十集[季终]
托妮
Tawney?
你收到后一定给我回电话
Please call me when you get this.
让我知道你没事
Got to let me know you're okay.
给我留个言就行  好吗  我不会回复
Just leave a message, all right? I won't answer.
我就从冰箱里拿东西
I just grabbed things from the refrigerator,
一边哭  一边往包里塞东西
crying and... dumping stuff in a bag --
我带走一个  留一个给小泰
"I'll take one, I'll leave Teddy one.
I'll take one, I'll leave Teddy one."
我当时就只想着  我得吃东西啊
My overriding thought was, "I have to have food."
真是太不理性了
That's not rational.
也可能是太理性了
Maybe it's too rational.
那种压力之下  不同的人
Different people do different things
会做不同的事
under that kind of stress.
我明显是储藏食物
I evidently hoard food.
我觉得这次野餐我们不需要搅打奶油了
I don't think we need the whipping cream at this picnic.
跟你带的玉米片一起吃怎么样
Maybe on your corn chips?
这主意我没想到
Well, I hadn't thought of that.
那
Well...
我们就试试吧
Let's see.
咸咸的  甜甜的  脆脆的
The salty, the sweet, the crunch --
其实也不难吃
It's actually not bad.
-真的吗  -假的  很难吃
- Really? - No, it's bad.
我饿了
Uh, I was hungry.
吃点东西对你有好处
It's good for you to eat.
应该吧
I guess.
我拿走了
May I?
谢谢
Thank you.
我如此习惯他  对我生气
I was so used to him... being mad at me.
我从未见他如此脆弱...
I'd never seen him so broken-down like that...
如此崩溃
So shattered.
你签了协议是不是就再也不能回来了
You can never come back here if you sign those papers?
对
No.
代价太高了  丹尼尔
Such a price to pay, Daniel.
不高
Not really.
怎么了  丹尼尔
What is it, Daniel?
你离开前...
Before you leave...
在你决定未来的生活之前
Before you decide what your life may be,
我需要告诉你件事  托妮
I need to tell you something, Tawney.
是关于小泰的
It's about Teddy.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他最近遇到了很多事
He's been dealing with a lot lately --
你不知道的事
Things you don't know about.
你知道吗
And -- and you do?
洗礼之后
After the baptism,
他让我远离你
he told me to stay away from you.
他是你丈夫  我知道他这么做是对的
He was your husband, and I know he was right.
我也告诉他我会远离你
And I told him I would.
然后他还说了些别的事
Then he said some other things.
什么事
What things?
就是  一堆话而已
Just words... lined up together.
我以前都听过
I've heard them before.
反正都差不多
Similar, anyway.
虽然还是那些话  但他很担心
They're just words, but he was afraid.
他担心会失去你
He was afraid of losing you.
但当时我没看出来
But I couldn't see that then.
我伤害了他  侮辱了他
I hurt him... humiliated him.
那是我在监狱中学的
Something I learned in prison.
可以让一个男人觉得  无助
Something to make a man feel...powerless.
那不是强奸
It wasn't rape.
但却很暴力
But it was violent.
而且...
And...
而且什么
And what?
会让人发疯
Unhinged.
我希望时光能倒流
I wish I could go back.
因为他不该受此侮辱
Because he didn't deserve that.
他不该带着那种烦扰度过余生
And he doesn't deserve to have to live with it.
他什么都没说
He never said anything.
我一直以为是因为我
I always thought it was me.
小泰
Hey, Teddy.
妈妈
Hey, mom.
我在忙活店里的账本
Just doing the books for the store.
谢谢你  我知道很麻烦
Well, we appreciate it. I-I know that can be a pain.
哪有
Not at all.
不要告诉泰德  不过我还挺想让他知道的
Don't tell Ted, but I kind of look forward to it.
话说你今早来有什么事吗
So, what brings you here this morning?
丹尼尔在吗
Uh, is Daniel around?
他昨晚没回家
Well, he didn't come in last night.
我知道  小泰
I know, Teddy.
不过他现在正处在
It's just where he is right now,
人生的关键时期
you know, in his life.
从某种程度上说他就像个孩子
He's like an adolescent in some ways.
就应该让他去体会吧
Just got to let him go through it, I guess.
是啊
I guess.
他现在可能在阿曼莎那里
He -- he might be at Amantha's by now.
乔恩好像要跟他谈几件事
I think Jon had to talk over a few things with him.
他要接受认罪协议吗
So, is he gonna take the plea deal?
我不知道  亲爱的
I don't know, honey.
我知道他不想回监狱了
I know he doesn't want to go back to jail.
他已经在考虑搬走了
He's already talking about moving.
搬去哪里
Where?
不清楚  反正要离开波利
I'm not sure. Away from Paulie.
一切都发生得太快了
It's all happening so quick.
小泰
Teddy...
你的手怎么回事
What's happened to your hand?
我没注意
I, uh... I-I got distracted
被门夹了
and got it caught in a door.
没事  没事
Oh, it's fine. It's fine.
小泰  你还好吗
Teddy, you okay?
我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
小泰
Teddy.
跟我可以说实话
It's me you're talking to.
孩子没了
We lost the baby.
托妮流产了
Tawney miscarried.
天哪  太遗憾了  亲爱的
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
医生说  这很正常
The doctor said, uh, it's nature's way.
知道吗
You know?
这种事很常见
These things are pretty common.
比大家想的还要常见
Happen more often than people think.
确实如此
That's true.
但还是挺可惜的
But, still, that's sad.
确实
It is that.
托妮还好吗
How's Tawney dealing with it?
这个真的不好说
It's hard to tell, really.
当然了
Of course.
现在她心情一定很复杂
Things must be so complicated for her right now.
过来  亲爱的
Come here, honey.
我完全支持你  桑德拉
You have my full support, now, Sondra.
我想让你知道这点
I want you to know that.
这对我意义重大  议员
That means a lot, Senator.
我还以为霍顿不会同意流放
I wasn't sure Holden would go for banishment.
你说的话一定很有说服力
You must've been very persuasive.
他还没签字
Well, he hasn't signed off on it yet.
如果不签  你用撤销保释威胁他了吗
Did you threaten to revoke his bond if he doesn't?
是的
I did.
你真的会撤销吗
Would you?
我当然会考虑这么做
I would certainly consider it.
明白了
I see.
哪位法官来签发他的认罪协议
And what judge will sign off on this plea deal?
凯尔特法官
Judge Kelter.
我需要担心吗
Should I worry?
说实话  你得时刻注意  桑德拉
Well, you should always worry, Sondra, generally speaking,
但尤其是这位马库斯·凯尔特法官
But especially with the honorable Marcus Kelter.
这个案子在某些方面
He'll need some hand-holding
你得跟他说清楚...
on certain aspects of this case --
首先  为什么撤掉强奸指控
Why you dropped the rape charge, for one.
没有精样  没有目击证人
No sperm, no witness.
但他还是会要细节  具体细节
He'll still want details -- specific details.
什么意思
Meaning?
盘问霍顿
Have Holden debrief.
让他回想谋杀案发生的那一夜
Have him walk us through the night of the murder --
让他重新说一遍
His latest version.
我知道盘问是什么
I know what a debrief is.
这样凯尔特问起
That way, when Kelter asks
你为什么不起诉霍顿强奸汉娜时
why you didn't charge Holden with Hanna's rape,
你就可以把重点转移到那句
you can point to the transcript where it says,
"我杀了她  我没强奸她"上了
"I killed her -- I didn't rape her."
那他也得这样说啊
If he says that.
他签掉协议就好了
It would just be better if he signs the confession.
他最好这么说
He better say it.
如果他不愿意坦白
What's the point of his plea
那认罪有什么意义
if he's not willing to confess?
我们不就是为了让他坦白一切吗
Isn't that what this is all about?
现在增加要求有点晚了  罗兰
It's a little late in the game to add demands, Roland --
尤其是再盘问他
Especially a debrief.
我想听他亲口承认
I want to hear it from the horse's mouth.
我不想让别人说
I don't want there to be any talk
这个认罪协议只是为了我们的面子
that this was a-a plea deal to save face on our side.
你呢
Do you?
当然不想
Of course not.
我只是觉得
I-I just can't imagine
斯特恩先生不会允许自己的委托人经历那种事
that Mr. Stern would allow his client to go through that.
经历什么
Through what?
最后一次承认自己杀了人的羞耻感吗
The humiliation of having to answer for his actions once and for all?
我觉得凯尔特法官
I can't imagine judge Kelter
在没有盘问的情况下不会签发协议
signing off on a plea agreement without one.
其实  我可以保证他不会签发
In fact, I can guarantee you he won't.
一定要盘问他  桑德拉
Get the debrief, Sondra,
否则你的一切努力都要打水漂了
or all your good work will likely be for naught.
乔治
George.
你好  乔治
Hello! George!
有人在家吗
Anybody home?
乔治
George?
亲爱的乔治  我来看你了
把你家的墙弄坏了  抱歉
丹尼尔·霍顿
丹尼尔  听我说
Daniel, listen to me.
要求重新盘问证实了我们以前的想法
Asking for the debrief affirms what we already knew --
他们根本不知道那晚发生了什么事
They really have no idea what happened that night.
现在他们想让你帮他们捋清事情的经过
Now they're asking you to fill in the blanks for them.
我随便编点说说可以吗
Is it all right if I just make something up?
如果他们想立案起诉你
If they want to build a case against you,
那就让他们从头开始吧
let them start from scratch.
从头  我已经认罪了
Scratch? I confessed.
这个我会帮你搞定的
I'll get it thrown out.
真的吗  乔恩
Will you really, Jon?
这次跟第一次审判不一样  丹尼尔
This wouldn't be like your first trial, Daniel,
如果再次审判的话
if it came to that.
你现在拥有
You would have resources
当时你们家人没有的资源
your family didn't have back then.
司法部很重视这案子
Justice row is all in.
即使他们真的撤销你的保释
Look, even if they did revoke your bond,
我们也可以申请电子监控什么的
we would push for some sort of electronic monitoring.
你顶多也就被关个一两天
You wouldn't be in custody for more than a day or two.
然后就可以回家了
Then you could go home.
那到场的会有谁
So, who would be there?
什么到场
What?
审讯盘问的时候
At the debrief.
现任检察官和前任检察官
The current prosecutor and the former.
福克斯先生
Mr. Foulkes.
对  福克斯先生
Yes -- Mr. Foulkes.
可能警长也会到场
And probably the sheriff.
都是老朋友了
Old friends.
丹尼尔  你不该接受协议
Daniel, you shouldn't take the deal.
你已经说过了  乔恩
You've said that already, Jon.
向你传达他们提出的条件是我的职责
It was my duty to communicate their offer to you.
但是我非常明确地告诉你  如果再次上庭
But it is also my duty to tell you in the strongest terms
我知道我们能赢
that if we went to trial, I know we can win.
我会考虑你的提议
I will take your counsel under advisement.
与此同时  好好处理认罪协议的事
In the meantime, move ahead with the deal --
包括重新审讯盘问
debrief included.
早弄早好
The sooner, the better.
你为什么这么做  丹尼尔
Why are you doing this, Daniel?
很简单
It's not complicated.
我只想让这件事快点结束  乔恩
I just want it to be over, Jon.
你不想吗
Don't you?
我不想这样结束
Not this way, no.
人不会总是如愿以偿
Can't always get what you want.
你最近见过住18号的乔治·梅尔顿吗
You seen George Melton lately, over in number 18?
没有
Nope.
我看到你们家门前有摄像头
I saw you have security cameras on the property.
那些...
Are those --
是真的吗  是真的
Real? Yeah, they real.
而且大部分时间可以正常使用
Work, too -- mostly.
你点击菜单
You click up to the menu.
就可以看到具体日期
That lets you look at the specific days.
然后可以快进快退
And you can toggle up and down here.
好  我知道了  谢谢
All right, I'll figure it out. Thanks.
乔治亚州的警长在这里都有管辖权吗
I didn't know Georgia sheriffs had jurisdiction down here.
我不是以警长的身份来的
I'm here unofficially.
不到万不得已我可不想招惹是非
Don't want to poke the snake 'less I have to.
这我没意见
I don't have a problem with that.
明天见
See y'all tomorrow.
亲爱的
Well, hey, sweetie.
你不用今天就把账本送过来的
You didn't have to bring the books by today.
反正我也得去杂货店买点东西
Well, I have to pick up some things at the grocery store,
所以...
so...
这个月业绩不错
We had a pretty good month.
我感觉应该比上几个月好点
I thought it might've been a little bit better than the last few.
看看这些轮辋
Look at all the rims.
他做得太棒了
He's done such a great job with this.
确实不错
It's pretty impressive, all right.
我觉得因为他来买轮胎的人好像也多了
I think he's even brought in a few more tire customers.
这是双赢
It's a win-win.
是啊
Yep.
我喜欢这个
I like these.
我应该找他租来用用
I think I might try to work out a deal with him.
珍妮特
Janet...
我有些消息
I've got some news.
但我真的不想告诉你
I really don't want to have to tell you this.
他来家里了
He came by the house.
谁
Who?
小泰
Teddy.
他告诉你了吗
He told you?
告诉我了
He did.
这种事常有  泰德
It happens, Ted --
比人们以为的还要经常发生
more often than people realize.
要流产的话还是早点为好
It's better to have an early miscarriage
总比孩子大了强
than a late one.
怀丹尼尔之前我就流过一次
I had one before Daniel.
还记得我告诉过你吗
Remember I told you about that?
当然记得
Of course.
托妮年轻坚强  他们会熬过去的
Tawney's young and strong. They'll get through this.
当然了
I'm sure they will.
不过我还是有点震惊
Still... a bit of a shock.
是啊
Of course.
很遗憾  泰德
I'm sorry, Ted.
总有一天你会当爷爷的
You'll be a granddaddy someday.
霍顿  你有来访者
Holden. You've got a visiter.
是谁啊
Who is it?
妈妈让我代她问好
Mother sends her love.
我以为咱俩不见面会好点
I thought it'd be easier for us not to see each other.
但实际上  并非如此
But it's... not easier.
确实
No.
并非如此
It's not.
煤气公司干得怎么样
How's the gas company?
我升职了
They promoted me.
是吗
They did?
高级客服专家
Senior customer-service specialist.
也有自己的单间了
Got my own cubicle and everything.
像我一样
Just like me.
我希望你能回大学学习
I wish you'd go on back to college.
我会的
I will.
但事情总有个先后
First things first.
我有好消息告诉你  丹尼尔
Got some good news, Daniel.
司法部要派一个新律师来为你辩护
Justice row is sending down a new guy to represent you.
他们把一切都押上了
They are all-in.
真好
Well, that's great.
我们会救你出来的  丹尼
We're gonna get you out of here, Danny.
想玩猜字游戏[刽子手]吗
Want to play hangman?
猜字游戏
Hangman?
不合适吗
Inappropriate?
正相反  你先吧
The opposite. You go first.
好
Okay.
10个字母
10 letters.
里面有R吗
Is there an "R"?
没有
Nope.
这是你的脑袋
It's your head.
这可不是好兆头啊
Not looking good for our hero.
L呢
"L."
这里有个L
There is an "L."
干得漂亮
Nicely done.
现在我住在附近  我们每周都能一起玩
Now that I'm nearby, we could do this every week.
那简直是个残忍而罕见的惩罚
Well, that would be cruel and unusual punishment.
有T吗
How about a "T"?
对谁残忍啊
Cruel for who?
对你  妹妹
You, sister.
正相反呢  哥哥
Quite the opposite, brother.
天啊
My god.
我确实没想到会发展成这样
I sure didn't think it would turn out this way.
你得跟他谈谈  阿曼莎  要不就成真了
You have to talk to him, Amantha, or it's gonna happen.
我已经试过了  乔恩
I already tried, Jon.
可我们不能就这么放弃啊
We can't just give up, you know.
我一直在想你第一次出现
I've been thinking about that first time
谈起案子的时候
that you came down to talk about the case.
你无法想象你给我们带来了多大的希望
You can't imagine the hope that you gave us.
我只是在完成我的工作
Just trying to do my job.
不管丹尼尔做了什么决定
No matter what Daniel decides to do,
希望你都不要怪自己
I don't want you to blame yourself.
妈妈是对的
Mother's right.
毕竟  这是他的生活
At the end of the day, it's his life --
就像我的生活是我的  你的也属于你一样
just like it's my life, and just like it's your life.
我们都得为自己的决定
We all have to deal with the consequences
承担后果
of our decisions.
还没结束  阿曼莎
It's not over, Amantha.
我知道
I know it isn't.
但不管怎样
But regardless...
我觉得你应该接受波士顿的工作
I think you should take that job in Boston.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
我不会跟你去了  乔恩
I'm not coming with you, Jon.
不是因为认罪协议的事
It's not because of the plea deal.
好吧  是因为这事
Well... it is,
但只是因为这件事
but only in the way that it has forced me
强迫我去想我的生活中除了丹尼尔
to think about what I would want in my life
真正想要的是什么
outside of all things Daniel.
那里面没有我吗
And that doesn't include me?
我不知道  乔恩
I don't know, Jon.
也许有吧
Maybe.
我不知道我想要什么
I don't know what I want.
我只知道我过去想要的是什么
I only know what I wanted.
我懂了
I hear you,
而且我也理解你的想法  阿曼莎
and I understand where you're coming from, Amantha.
真的
I really do.
但我不会放弃我们俩的爱情的
But I'm not giving up on us --
就像我不会放弃丹尼尔的事一样
any more than I'm giving up on Daniel.
我只是怕
I just wonder if we won't...
我们总会让对方想起
somehow always remind each other
这件倒霉的悲剧
of this whole goddamn tragedy.
比如一些表情或者话语
Some look or some word.
或是我们俩就是因为它才走到了一起的事实
Or just because it's how we came together.
还是等认罪协议的事解决了
Let's just wait until this plea deal is resolved
我们再决定我们之间该怎么办吧
before we make any decisions one way or the other.
好啊  乔恩
Sure, Jon.
快点  加布里尔  快点
Come on, Gabriel! Faster, faster!
孩子们  等等  等等妈妈
Guys, wait! Wait for mommy!
圣经
你好  泰德
Hello, Ted.
妈妈呢
Where's mother?
楼上
Upstairs.
你有什么心事  泰德
What's on your mind, Ted?
人不该听信一面之词  丹尼尔
There's two sides to every story, Daniel.
我觉得这话很对
I've learned that much.
我也知道小泰不是完人
And I know Teddy's no angel.
但是我完全无法理解
But I cannot for the life of me
你到底是以什么样的心境
understand what your side of the story would be
能对他做出那样的事
to cause you to do what you did to him.
除非这事不是真的
Unless it's a lie.
是真的  泰德
It's no lie, Ted.
我确实那么做了
I'm guilty as charged.
那你告诉我  我们该怎么办  丹尼尔
Then tell me how we make this right, Daniel,
我们怎样才能维持这个家
how we exist as a family now --
我们要怎么告诉你妈妈
how we even tell your mother.
告诉他妈妈什么
Tell your mother what?
出什么事了
What's happened?
我有事要告诉你  妈妈
There's something I have to tell you, mother.
一切都会好的  泰德
Everything's gonna be okay, Ted.
什么会好的
What is?
我接受认罪协议
I'm taking the plea deal.
但其中有一条
But one of the stipulations is that...
我得离开波利
I have to leave Paulie.
其实是得离开这个州
The entire state, essentially.
要多久
For how long?
嗯
Well...
永远吧
forever.
我得关门了  警长
I need to close up, Sheriff.
再等几分钟  行吗
Just a couple more minutes, all right?
搞什么
What the hell?
大日子吧
Big day, huh?
开始有这种感觉了
It's beginning to feel that way.
你告诉妈妈被驱逐的事了
So, you told mom about the banishment?
是的
I did.
那盘问的事呢
And the debrief?
告诉她有什么意义呢
What would've been the point?
离开时良心好受些吧
Walk away with a clear conscience, maybe?
如果这是你的目的
If that's your aim.
我不是来劝你改主意的  丹尼尔
I'm not here to change your mind, Daniel.
所以你不用担心
So you don't have to worry.
乔恩是想让我试试的
Jon wanted me to try.
乔恩啊
Dear jon.
那你来干什么
Then why are you here?
你这么做之后
'cause after you do this,
我也将不再是从前的我了
I'm not gonna be the same person anymore, and...
所以我想再当一次之前的我
I wanted to be this person with you one more time.
那你要成为什么人
Who are you gonna be?
我不知道
I don't know.
我希望不是个讨人厌的人
I hope it won't be a bitter person.
我也希望
Me too.
你不想被免罪  是吗
You don't want to be exonerated, do you?
我不只是想救你出狱  丹尼尔
I didn't just want to get you out, Daniel.
我希望能为你正名  为我们正名
I wanted to clear your name -- our name.
你可以说
And you can say
别人怎么想是别人的事
that people are gonna think what they're gonna think,
但还是有区别的
but... there is a difference.
有区别的
There is a difference.
那就改个名字吧  阿曼莎
Then change your name, Amantha.
如果你承认是你杀了汉娜
If you go in there and say that you killed Hanna
而且事实如此  那可以
and it's the truth, then so be it.
但如果你承认是你杀了她
But if you go in there and say that you killed her
仅仅是因为你不想再面对这一切
just because you don't want to deal with this anymore
或是只把这当游戏  或者只是耍性子
or play the game or keep fighting the good fight,
那你就是个懦夫  丹尼尔
then you are a coward, Daniel.
你更希望是哪一种呢  妹妹
Which would you rather it be, sister?
我不知道你要去哪儿或是想做什么
I don't know where you're going or what you're gonna do,
但是我再也不会联系你了
but I will never reach out to you again.
如果你的生活中需要我
If you want me in your life,
那你得主动来找我
you're gonna have to reach out to me,
我不会置之不理的
and I won't hold my breath.
谢谢你打电话来
Thanks for calling.
我不想你担心或者疑惑
I didn't want you to worry or wonder.
我一直都很担心
I'm always gonna worry.
你的手怎么了  小泰
What happened to your hand, Teddy?
打架弄伤的
Got in a fight.
昨天晚上你住哪儿了
Where you been sleeping?
汽车旅馆
At a motel.
还以为你会给凯特或是
Thought maybe you'd call Kate or...
教堂认识的人打电话
somebody from church.
我只想一个人待着
I just needed to be alone.
晚点儿可能会给她或凯西小姐打电话
Probably will call her... or Miss Kathy later.
只是得先想清楚一些事情
Just need to figure some things out first.
你准备去哪里想清楚
Where you gonna do that?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
还有什么需要吗
Anything you need?
暂时没什么需要
I'm okay for now.
如果你遇到困难
If you get stuck...
或是需要帮助
or need help...
你可以随时给我打电话
You can always call me,
如果你不想跟我说话  可以给爸妈打电话
or call mom and dad if you don't want to talk to me.
他们愿意为你做任何事
They'd do anything for you.
我知道了
I know.
小泰  我
Teddy, I...
我不知道该如何开口  但是
I don't know exactly how to say this, but...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我为丹尼尔对你所做的事
I'm so sorry...
感到非常抱歉
for what Daniel did to you.
他告诉你了吗
He told you?
在汽车旅馆
At the motel.
我很遗憾你没能告诉我
I'm sorry you couldn't tell me.
他夺走了一切
He's taken everything.
夺走了我的全部
Taken it all from me.
那是什么
What is that?
已经无关紧要了
Doesn't matter now.
是给我的吗
Is it for me?
无所谓了
It's nothing.
他无权如此  托妮
He had no right, Tawney.
他回来之前  我们很幸福
We were happy... before he came back.
我们曾经很幸福  托妮
We were happy, Tawney.
不是吗
Weren't we?
我很抱歉  小泰
I'm sorry, Teddy.
请进
Come in.
你把随身听还给我了
You returned my walkman.
我听了那个随身听
I listened to it.
你当然听了
Of course you did.
她爱过你吗
Did she love you?
她那时才16
She was 16.
你爱过她吗
Did you love her?
我喜欢过她
I liked her.
今天你打算说是你杀的她吗
Are you gonna say you killed her today?
也许会
Probably.
你离开波利以后  我还能再见到你吗
Will I ever see you again after you leave Paulie?
大概见不到了
Probably not.
我想也是
I didn't think so.
暂时不要告诉妈妈  好吗
Don't tell mother for a while, okay?
今天你要用我的自行车吗
Do you need my bike today?
不用
No.
不过谢谢你让我用它
Thanks for letting me use it, though.
你能骑它我很高兴
I liked knowing you were riding it.
车不错
It's a good bike.
再见
See ya.
不系领带吗
No tie?
你能帮我系领带吗
Can you tie it for me?
当然可以
Of course.
阿曼莎选的这条领带吧
Amantha picked out this tie, didn't she?
是  是她选的
Yes, she did.
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
你在城市里可能会过得很好
You might do well in a city...
譬如说  一个能让你融入生活的地方
somewhere where you might... blend in the soup, so to speak.
你说得没错
You might be right.
有很多不错的城市距离这儿只有几个小时行程
A lot of nice cities just a few hours away,
查塔诺加  哥伦比亚
Chattanooga, Columbia,
克逊维尔  伯明翰
Jacksonville, Birmingham.
全在阿拉巴马州吗  妈妈
Alabama, mother?
好吧
Well...
丹尼尔  我们得走了
Daniel, we should go.
莫比尔市怎么样
How about Mobile?
在海湾地区
On the gulf.
是的
It is.
一会儿见
See you in a bit.
-下午好  -下午好
- Good afternoon. - Afternoon.
你们都看过这份认罪协议了吧
Did you both have a chance to review the proffer letter?
看了  它涵盖了我们所讨论的一切
We did. Looks like it covers everything we discussed.
你一旦签了这个
Once you sign this,
你在这里所说的一切都不能用于指证你了
nothing you say here can ever be used against you.
你还要再看看吗
Do you want to have another look?
真实
Truthful...
完整
complete...
全部责任
full responsibility...
毫不回避
without evasion.
波利法院
你当时和汉娜·迪恩在河边
You were down at the river with Hanna Dean.
你们都服了致幻蘑菇
You'd both just taken psychoactive mushrooms.
你们当时做了什么
What did you do then?
我们正在亲热
We were making out.
她脱掉了上衣
She took her shirt off.
你们发生性关系了吗
Did you have sexual relations?
她想发生  但是
She wanted to, but, uh...
我做不到
I, uh...couldn't.
我无法勃起
Couldn't get an erection.
她开始大笑
She started... laughing.
我想当时我心烦意乱  吓坏了
I got upset, freaked out, I guess.
她说没关系
She said it didn't matter,
但是她一直嘲笑我
but she just kept laughing at me.
我不喜欢那样  所以
I didn't like it, so...
发生什么了
What happened?
如我妹妹所说  我就是个懦夫  我逃跑了
I was a coward, like my sister said. I ran away.
你是说  你们在两厢情愿或其他情况下
So are you stating that you did not have
都并没有发生性关系吗
sexual intercourse, consensual or otherwise?
是的
I am.
你离开她以后发生了什么
Well, what happened after you left her?
我在树林里迷路了
I got lost... in the woods.
一直在原地打转儿
Kept getting turned around.
我最后来到那片陡岸上
I finally ended up on this... on this bluff.
就在河上方  然后我看到了汉娜
It was just above the river, and...I saw Hanna.
她就在下面  我离开她的地方
She was down there where I'd left her.
那时汉娜还活着吗  丹尼尔
Was Hanna still alive at this point, Daniel?
活着
Very.
但她不是独自一人
But now she's not alone.
当时还有其他人
Now there were others...
乔治  特雷
George, Trey.
还有谁
Who were the others?
还有
There was...
克里斯托弗
Christopher.
我记不清了
I don't remember.
克里斯托弗  姓什么
Christopher who?
当时天很黑  但我能看清他们的脸
It was dark, but I could see their faces,
他们的身子交缠在一起
their bodies all intertwined.
汉娜在跟他们做爱
Hanna was doing things to them...
触摸着  抓紧着
touching and... grabbing...
吸吮着
sucking.
你那时做了什么  霍顿先生
And what did you do then, Mr. Holden?
你那时做了什么
What did you do then?
我愣住了
I just froze.
只是站在那里看着那一切
Just stood there and watched.
然后他们看到了我
Then they saw me,
他们发现我看见他们了
and... and they watched me watch them.
特雷看见我了
Trey saw me.
他不在意
He didn't care.
他们只是继续为所欲为
They all just did what they wanted.
为所欲为做什么  霍顿先生
Did what, Mr. Holden?
我以为汉娜是在
I thought Hanna was...
我以为她是想用他们来羞辱我  你明白吗
I thought she was trying to taunt me with them, you know?
之后我才意识到
It's only later that I-I realized
她根本不知道自己在做什么
that she didn't know what she was doing.
她陷得太深了
Got in too deep.
她才16岁
She was 16.
是我给了她蘑菇
I had given her the mushrooms.
然后我转身走了
I just turned away.
之后你做了什么
What did you do then?
我看到树倒下
I watched the trees falling.
我到下面一看
And then I went down there.
她已经死了
And she was dead.
就这样吗
That's it?
跑到那边  她已死了
Went down there, she was dead?
她蜷缩在一起
She was all bent up.
最伤人的并非丑恶
You see, it's the beauty that hurts the most.
而是极美的事物
Not the ugly.
我们给你这个认罪协议
We didn't offer this deal so we could sit here
不是为了坐在这里听你胡说八道
and listen to you spout lunacy
撒谎说你没杀汉娜·迪恩
and then lie about your role in Hanna Dean's murder.
这是什么
What is this?
我在唤起他的记忆
I'm jogging his memory.
丹尼尔  你不必回答
Daniel, you don't have to put up with any of this.
不  不
No. No.
这就是记忆的妙处所在  记忆是可变的
That's the thing about memory, it's malleable.
记忆是不定的  跟时间和承诺一样
It's elastic, like time and promises.
你一直都很帮我  福克斯先生
You've always been so helpful, Mr. Foulkes,
让我恢复记忆  给我看这些
Getting me to remember, showing me these...
照片
...Pictures...
告诉我我肯定勒死了她
...And telling me how I must've strangled her.
我没有
I never said that.
我肯定...
Oh, I must've been --
我肯定把你想成警长了
I must've been thinking about the sheriff --
前警长
The former sheriff --
磁带放完后  他向我解释我是怎么杀死她的
How he explained how she died when the tape recorder was off.
我是怎么脱了她的衣服
Told me how I had taken her clothes off
强奸了她
and raped her.
而我自始至终
And all the while,
都在等我的父亲
me just sitting there waiting for my father
因为你向我保证一旦我说实话
because you promised me that I would get to see him
我就可以见到他
once I just gave you the truth.
你向我保证我可以回家
You promised me that I could go home.
但我没能回家
But I didn't go home.
我也没强奸她  对吧
And I didn't rape her, did I?
你错了
You were wrong.
你们都大吃一惊吗
Are you at all surprised?
斯特恩先生  我忍不了了
Mr. Stern, I can't allow any more of this.
如果你的客户想达成这份认罪协议
If your client wants this plea,
那他就得老实回答这些问题
he's got to answer these questions truthfully.
能给我们点时间吗  谢谢
Can you give us a minute, please?
谢谢
Please?
丹尼尔  我们不接受协议好了
Daniel, let's just walk away, buddy.
跟他们法庭见
Tell them we'll see them in court.
她在那里跳舞时好美
She looked so beautiful dancing there.
你在犯傻
You're not thinking right.
我没有  乔恩
I am, Jon.
去把他们带进来
Just go ahead and bring them back in.
丹尼尔
Daniel.
乔恩  现在就去
Jon. Now.
她怎么死的  霍顿
How did she die, Holden?
我不想让她裸露着
I didn't want her to be u-uncovered,
所以我摘了些野花
So I-I got some wildflowers,
放在了她的私处上
put them on her in her private places.
我
I just...
把她的腿合起来
...put her legs back together.
我在她头发里放了花葱
And I-I placed Jacob's ladder in her hair.
她不再笑了
She wasn't laughing anymore.
我甚至都不知道我为什么会难过
I don't even know why I got upset.
但她当时
She was so...
好难过
So sad.
所以我坐在她身边
So I sat with her...
直到太阳升起
Till the sun came up.
然后警长来了
Then the sheriff came,
你当时也在房间里
And you -- you were there in the room.
你问我发生了什么
And you asked me what happened.
你说你记不得了
You said you didn't remember.
起初我的确是记不得了  但
Well, a-at first, I-I didn't, but...
你不停给我看这些照片
Then y-you kept showing me these pictures
试图还原真相
Trying to explain,
但根本说不通
but it still didn't make any sense.
我已经麻木
But I was numb.
我被关在那个房间里好几个小时
I-I'd been in that room... For hours.
所以我只好
So I just said what I...
撒了谎
I needed to say...
为了出去见我父亲
To get out... To see my father.
而你没有阻止
And you let me say it.
你让我说了
You let me.
我让你说你想说的  丹尼尔
I let you say what you wanted to say, Daniel.
我让你说出实话
I let you unburden yourself.
可能细节不清楚
Maybe the details were foggy,
但事实很清楚
but the truth was as clear as day.
现在也是如此
It remains so.
你说了我可以回家
You said I could go home.
你杀了汉娜·迪恩吗
Did you kill Hanna Dean?
如果我承认是我杀的  你这次会让我回家吗
If I say I did, will you let me go this time?
没人逼你承认  对吧
No one made you kill her, did they?
如果我承认是我杀的  你会放我走吗
If I say I did, will you let me go?
告诉我  没人逼你承认  对吧
Tell me -- no one made you kill her, did they?
没人
No.
他们没有
They didn't.
她怎么死的  丹尼尔
How did she die, Daniel?
丹尼尔
Daniel.
我只是用手勒住她的脖子
I-I just put my hands around her neck...
使劲掐
Squeezed as hard as I could.
直到怎么样
Until what?
直到她死
Until she was gone.
我杀了她
I killed her.
没人逼你这么说
And no one put words in your mouth.
没人逼你承认
No one coerced your confession.
对吧
Did they?
没错
No.
他们没有
They didn't.
我们完事了吗
Are we done?
我们完事了
We're done.
刚才怎么回事  丹尼尔
What just happened in there, Daniel?
记忆涌现
Memories.
你该坐坐
you should sit.
可能要等一会他们才会把认罪协议呈给法官
It might be a while before we present the plea to the judge.
我坐了好几个小时了
I've been sitting for hours.
那好吧
Not a problem.
我们这里有一套不错的轮胎
We got a nice set of tires.
还有各种轮辋
We can -- we can get all kinds of rims.
孩子们更喜欢螺旋型
The kids, they tend to go for the spinners.
但这种可能...
Uh, but this one might be...
你在莫比亚有认识的人吗
Do you know anyone in Mobile?
没有
I don't.
这就是它吸引人的地方吧
You might say that's one of its attractions.
怎么样了
So, how'd it go?
他说他杀了她  但没强奸她
He said he killed her but didn't rape her.
TW建筑
他有说为什么杀了她吗
Well, did he say why he killed her?
我需要你去亚特兰大一趟
I need you to run up to Atlanta.
让实验室做这上面的DNA检测
Run these to the lab. Have them do DNA testing.
互相做吗
To each other?
跟汉娜·迪恩的比对
Or to Hanna Dean.
特雷·威利斯
Trey Willis?
这上面全是那混蛋的DNA
Son of a bitch licked it.
太迟了吗
Is it too late?
卡尔
Carl?
太迟了吗
Is it too late?
我不知道
I don't know.
我打电话问问
I'll make a call.
抱歉  我接下电话
Excuse me. Let me take this.
你好
Yes, sir?
我去看看怎么还没好
Better go see what's taking them so long.
欧文  走吧
Owen, come on.
怎么了
What's wrong?
拿走吧
Take it.
不了  我...
Uh, no, I...
拿走什么都行
Take anything you want.
全拿走吧
Take it all.
算是帮我们的忙
You'll be doing us a favor.